Logan Thomas

Senior Associate Data Scientist I Protection Engineering Consultants Austin, TX



About me

I'm a highly motivated and naturally curious individual with 6 years of experience using data science & machine learning techniques.

I exhibit an analytical and detailoriented nature, while placing strong value on building relationships.

Skills



Contact



✓ logan.thomas005@gmail.com

(321) 961-9107

in logan-thomas

loganthomas

Experience

Senior Associate Data Scientist I

Protection Engineering Consultants: Austin, TX Advanced Technology & Research Team Aug 2020 - Present

- Developed evolutionary algorithm library for deploying multi-gene genetic programming and symbolic regression
- Enhanced computer vision algorithms for autonomous fragment tracking
- · Python technical lead and Git evangelist
- Security Clearance as of Sept 2020

Course Instructor

DataCamp: Austin, TX Feb 2019 - Present

- Created "Writing Efficient Python Code" course
- 20k+ students, 4 hours of content, 4.5/5 average course rating

Lead Data Scientist

Nielsen: Austin, TX Machine Learning & Algorithms Team Oct 2018 - Aug 2019

- Researched and implemented machine learning models
- Discovered realationships and deteced anomolies in large datasets
- Synthesized disparate datasets to influence decision making

Senior Data Scientist

Nielsen: San Francisco, CA Digital Product Team Aug 2016 - Oct 2018

- Slected as top talent to particitpate in prestigious early career training program
- Launched automated Natural Languate Processing enginge leveraging network analysis, graph theory, and term frequenct-inverse document frequenct methods
- Deployed autonomous training pipeline for LSTM deep learning model using Databricks, AWS, Tensorflow, and Keras
- Enigneered end-to-end optimization routine utilizing random forest models, kdimensional trees, and CVXPY



Education

University of Florida (2012 - 2014)

Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering Minor in Statistics

Palm Beach Atlantic University (2008 - 2012)

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics Minor in Biblical Studies; Graduated Summa Cum Laude

<> Contributions

Open Source:

P pyjanitor P deap P pint

Personal:

P turkey-bowl P repo-scrape P python-practice